[
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Japanese author to receive the Nobel Prize in Literature?",
        "answer": "Yasunari Kawabata"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many troops can governors send with a level 17 City Hall or above?",
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"Last of the Romans\" is an epithet used to describe someone With a classical Roman way of thinking. Who would NOT exemplify that?",
        "answer": "Attila"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why was the Dead Sea given this name?",
        "answer": "The high saline water prevents plants and animals from thriving near it"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many troops can governors send with a level 17 City Hall or above?",
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first Japanese author to receive the Nobel Prize in Literature?",
        "answer": "Yasunari Kawabata"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Julius Caesar's nickname?",
        "answer": "The Uncrowned King"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where was the World Heritage Terracotta Army found?",
        "answer": "In a royal mausoleum"
    },
    {
        "question": "The famous Renaissance sculpture Pietà was the work of which artist?",
        "answer": "Michelangelo"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is the correct description for the stratosphere?",
        "answer": "It is warm above and cold below"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these effects is NOT caused by Aethelflaed's skills?",
        "answer": "Healing slightly wounded units"
    },
    {
        "question": "From the 8th to the 11th century CE, what did Europeans frequently call the Scandinavian invaders who frequently ravaged their lands?",
        "answer": "Vikings"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following commanders was effectively the ruler of their kingdom, but never officially the head of state?",
        "answer": "Charles Martel"
    },
    {
        "question": "What level does your City Hall have to be to enter the Iron Age?",
        "answer": "Lvl 10"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Ancient Egypt, which of the following was NOT a privilege of being a 'Scribe'?",
        "answer": "Exempt from paying medical expenses if sick"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these animated movies was NOT directed by Hayao Miyazaki?",
        "answer": "Paprika"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which chapter of the Kingdom Chronicles grants the \"Explorer for Life\" achievement if all mist is explored before the chapter's end?",
        "answer": "Long Peace"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the Desire of Victory event, how can players gain rewards?",
        "answer": "Training troops"
    },
    {
        "question": "The 24 \"solar terms\" are a traditional Chinese calendar system used for what purpose?",
        "answer": "Agriculture"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country was England fighting against in the Battle of Agincourt?",
        "answer": "France"
    },
    {
        "question": "When Achilles refuses to fight, Patroclus puts on Achilles armor, fights the Trojans, and dies. Who is Patroclus killed by?",
        "answer": "Hector"
    },
    {
        "question": "Wales officially became part of the Kingdom of Great Britain during the reign of which King?",
        "answer": "Henry VIII"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following did NOT occur during the Greco-Persian Wars?",
        "answer": "The Battle of Agincourt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT a prerequisite for the Military Technology Cartography?",
        "answer": "Ballistics"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these circumstances would prevent you from changing civilization?",
        "answer": "Ongoing troop training in your city"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did the word \"marathon\" originally refer to?",
        "answer": "A place name"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these Commanders gets the ability to convert some slain units into severely wounded units when attacking a city?",
        "answer": "Charlemagne"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which vitamin deficiency can cause night blindness?",
        "answer": "Vitamin A"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which unit gains a strong benefit from Sun Tzu's \"Master Strategist\" skill?",
        "answer": "Infantry"
    },
    {
        "question": "The cathedral of Notre-Dame de Paris was built in which style?",
        "answer": "Gothic"
    },
    {
        "question": "Passport Pages are used when immigrating to other Kingdoms. What does the number of Passport Pages used depend on?",
        "answer": "Governor's Individual Power"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did the Late Show with David Letterman first premiere?",
        "answer": "1993"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hieroglyphs were part of which country's formal writing system?",
        "answer": "Ancient Egypt"
    },
    {
        "question": "By what other name is October also known under Japan's old calendar?",
        "answer": "Kannazuki"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT a \"low country\" of Europe?",
        "answer": "The United Kingdom"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Gallic rooster is an official national symbol of which country?",
        "answer": "France"
    },
    {
        "question": "What do you have to do to earn the Witness Protection achievement?",
        "answer": "Change your nickname 10 times"
    },
    {
        "question": "How do you obtain the Friend of the Kingdom achievement?",
        "answer": "Visit 100 tribal villages"
    },
    {
        "question": "The 1,000 point achievement chest includes:",
        "answer": "Epic Commander Sculpture"
    },
    {
        "question": "What achievement would spending over 200 Golden Keys in the Tavern in a single transaction unlock?",
        "answer": "All in"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the achievement obtained by acquiring 3 permanent city themes?",
        "answer": "Technicolor themes"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which achievement is unlocked from upgrading 2 hospitals to Lvl 25?",
        "answer": "Hale & Hearty"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following achievements must be completed before the \"Special Snowflake\" achievement?",
        "answer": "Long-range strike"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of Pelagius' passive skills?",
        "answer": "Charge"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country did Zarathustra, of the tone poem 'Thus Spoke Zarathustra', come from?",
        "answer": "Persia"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who founded the First Persian Empire?",
        "answer": "Cyrus the Great"
    },
    {
        "question": "What discovery made the deciphering of hieroglyphics possible?",
        "answer": "The Rosetta Stone"
    },
    {
        "question": "The borders of which of these countries extend across two continents?",
        "answer": "Egypt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why was British nurse Florence Nightingale known as \"The Lady with the Lamp\"?",
        "answer": "She would inspect patients at night"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the only King of England to be executed?",
        "answer": "Charles I"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where are the world's largest proven oil reserves located?",
        "answer": "Ghawar Field"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who founded the \"Malacca Sultanate\"?",
        "answer": "Parameswara"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which organ of the potato plant do we commonly eat?",
        "answer": "Stem"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which modern-day city was Shakespeare's Globe Theater built in?",
        "answer": "London"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Einstein publish his four Annus Mirabilis (\"Miracle Papers\")?",
        "answer": "1905"
    },
    {
        "question": "The concept of 'separation of powers' comes from which work by Montesquieu?",
        "answer": "The Spirit of Law"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Chinese mythology, what kind of creature is Jingwei?",
        "answer": "It's a bird!"
    },
    {
        "question": "Elbe day was the meeting of which two armies during World War II?",
        "answer": "USA, USSR"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT a component ingredient used to forge the Epic weapon \"Golden Age\"?",
        "answer": "Animal Bone"
    },
    {
        "question": "Pandas have 5 clawed toes on as well as a sixth digit. What do pandas use their sixth digit for?",
        "answer": "To hold Bamboo while eating"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these commander' Expertise Skill is the enhanced version of an existing skill?",
        "answer": "Björn Ironside"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who founded the \"Spanish Armada\"?",
        "answer": "Philip II"
    },
    {
        "question": "What useful tool did famed carpenter Lu Ban invent?",
        "answer": "The saw"
    },
    {
        "question": "What date is World Environment Day held each year?",
        "answer": "June 5th"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is considered a metallic resource?",
        "answer": "Iron"
    },
    {
        "question": "A human fingernail is made of which material?",
        "answer": "Alpha-keratin"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Mughal Empire carried Islam to where?",
        "answer": "Most of India"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who authored the tragedy \"Medea\"?",
        "answer": "Euripides"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Phoenician civilization originated in which part of the world?",
        "answer": "The Eastern Mediterranean"
    },
    {
        "question": "What race of creatures, mythical or otherwise, lived on Asgard according to Norse myth?",
        "answer": "Aesir"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Greek mythology, which hero quested for the Golden Fleece?",
        "answer": "Jason"
    },
    {
        "question": "You can help your allies build/upgrade buildings, research technologies, and heal troops. But how much does each help action fill the progress bar?",
        "answer": "0.01"
    },
    {
        "question": "What can \"Masonry\" technology help you to improve?",
        "answer": "The building speed of buildings in your city"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these countries did NOT participate in the Northern Seven Years' War (1563-1570)?",
        "answer": "The United Kingdom"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these holy sites grants a march speed bonus?",
        "answer": "Sanctum of Wind"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the Turkish straits that divide Europe from Asia?",
        "answer": "The Bosphorus"
    },
    {
        "question": "The military leader Charles Martel was NOT known for which of the following?",
        "answer": "Leading cavalary units"
    },
    {
        "question": "When were bicycles introduced to Europe?",
        "answer": "The 19th century"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these is an incorrect description of the \"Mare Imbrium\" on the moon?",
        "answer": "It contains a certain amount of sedimentary water"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these is used to rally alliance troops?",
        "answer": "Castle"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following descriptions of microscopes is false?",
        "answer": "They can be used to observe stars"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which title did Pierre de Coubertin, founder of the International Olympic Committee, hold?",
        "answer": "Baron"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Luger pistol, manufactured for the German army during WW2, uses which type of ammo?",
        "answer": "9mm Parabellum"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who owned everything in ancient Egyptian Kingdoms?",
        "answer": "The Pharaoh"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Commander's active skill can inflict Silence?",
        "answer": "Hermann"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which theater was Beethoven's Symphony No. 5 in C Minor debuted in 1808?",
        "answer": "The Theater an der Wien"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Norse mythology, what variety of trees was the World Tree?",
        "answer": "Ash"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT part of Mexico's flag?",
        "answer": "Camel"
    },
    {
        "question": "Shanghai's Jin Mao Tower has how many floors?",
        "answer": "88"
    },
    {
        "question": "What two major works are attributed to Homer?",
        "answer": "The Odyssey and The Iliad"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which technology comes right before Heavy Cavalry?",
        "answer": "Scale Armor"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Chieftain from the Ceroli Crisis event is well-versed in poison magic?",
        "answer": "Dekar"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is not a natural resource?",
        "answer": "Clothing"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which commander is known as \"The Immortal Hammer\"?",
        "answer": "Charles Martel"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the nationality of Pierre de Fermat, who proposed Fermat's Last Theorem?",
        "answer": "France"
    },
    {
        "question": "What age did ancient Greece enter after the Mycenaean civilization was destroyed?",
        "answer": "Dark Age"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which continent has the lowest average temperatures?",
        "answer": "Antarctica"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these is NOT considered one of the \"Five Good Emperors\" of the Nerva-Antonine dynasty of ancient Rome?",
        "answer": "Commodus"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of Julius Caesar's skills?",
        "answer": "Military Life"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following technologies precedes \"Horsemanship\"?",
        "answer": "Military Discipline"
    },
    {
        "question": "Charles Macintosh crafted a very early version of a raincoat from which material?",
        "answer": "Rubber"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which commander is commonly regarded as having exemplified the ideal of the \"Bushido Spirit\"?",
        "answer": "Kusonoki Masashige"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long did the Hundred Years' War between England and France last?",
        "answer": "116 years"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which year did Richard the Lionheart and Saladin sign a truce?",
        "answer": "1192"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is considered one of Confucius' disciples?",
        "answer": "Yan Hui"
    },
    {
        "question": "With whom did Minamoto no Yoshitsune raise an army to fight Taira no Kiyomori?",
        "answer": "Minamoto no Yoritomo"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many Olympic gold medals did African-American athlete Jesse Owens win in 1936?",
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following was written by Mary Shelley?",
        "answer": "Frankenstein"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who designed the \"Ottoman Cannon\"?",
        "answer": "Urban"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which military commander was known as the \"Teutoburg's Liberator\"?",
        "answer": "Hermann"
    },
    {
        "question": "What were the men and women hiding from on the outskirts of Florence in the novella collection \"The Decameron\"?",
        "answer": "The Black Plague"
    },
    {
        "question": "After its foundation in the 6th century BCE, which institution of the Roman Republic served as a consultative parliament?",
        "answer": "The Senate"
    },
    {
        "question": "What animal is the mascot of the 2022 Winter Olympics based on?",
        "answer": "Panda"
    },
    {
        "question": "Seondeok was Queen of Silla (part of modern-day Korea). What was her birth name?",
        "answer": "Kim Deokman"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Golden Bear Award is given out at which film festival?",
        "answer": "Berlin Film Festival"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why do frogs and other organism produce so many eggs/offspring?",
        "answer": "The more offspring produced the more likely they will survive"
    },
    {
        "question": "During the Trojan War, which Greek warrior killed Hector?",
        "answer": "Achilles"
    },
    {
        "question": "The novel Romance of the Three Kingdoms begins near the end of which Chinese dynasty?",
        "answer": "Han"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name for the phenomenon by which organisms that are better adapted to the environment survive to pass traits to their offspring?",
        "answer": "Natural selection"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Chieftain in the Ceroli Crisis event mounted a successful coup?",
        "answer": "Torgny"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state is home to the Walt Disney Company?",
        "answer": "California"
    },
    {
        "question": "French National Day is on July 14 in order to coincide with which historical event?",
        "answer": "Storming of the Bastille"
    },
    {
        "question": "In DC comics, what is Batman's real name?",
        "answer": "Bruce Wayne"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war was fought between the British houses of Lancaster and York for the throne of England?",
        "answer": "The Wars of the Roses"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which commander is reputed to have said, \"I came, I saw, I conquered\"?",
        "answer": "Julius Caesar"
    },
    {
        "question": "When did the War of the Austrian Succession take place?",
        "answer": "1740-1748"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these active skills belongs to Charles Martel?",
        "answer": "Shield of Francia"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these Alliance Skills increases damage versus barbarians and other neutral units?",
        "answer": "Unbridled Progress"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these is NOT one of Cao Cao's skills?",
        "answer": "Battle of Sorrow"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these is NOT one of the skills of Ceroli Chieftain Astrid?",
        "answer": "Flametongue's Kiss"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which city hosted the 2000 Summer Olympics?",
        "answer": "Sydney"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these Avatar Frames can be obtained from the Ceroli Crisis event?",
        "answer": "Undersea Kingdom"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which art group is known as a \"national treasure\" of Canada?",
        "answer": "Cirque du Soleil"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the only known short-period comet that is regularly visible to the naked eye from Earth?",
        "answer": "Halley's Comet"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where did reggae music originate?",
        "answer": "Jamaica"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is not an objective of Greek mythology?",
        "answer": "Provide a path for salvation"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which god is Taranis in Celtic mythology?",
        "answer": "Thunder God"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following works was written by the French playwright Pierre Corneille?",
        "answer": "Le Cid"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who wrote \"The Symposium\"?",
        "answer": "Plato"
    },
    {
        "question": "First created in Ancient Greece, to which profession does the Hippocratic Oath apply?",
        "answer": "Doctors"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who wrote Alice's Adventures in Wonderland?",
        "answer": "Lewis Carroll"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which prominent statesman served as the first Shogun of the Edo shogunate at the end of Japan's Warring States period?",
        "answer": "Tokugawa Ieyasu"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many times can you receive alliance help if your Alliance Center is level 14?",
        "answer": "18"
    },
    {
        "question": "In ROK, which of the following is NOT one of Mulan's skills?",
        "answer": "Clever Heart"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why do frogs and other organism produce so many eggs/offspring",
        "answer": "The more offspring produced the more likely they will survive"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who came up with the Trojan horse idea? Who won the Trojan War?",
        "answer": "Odysseus; The Greeks"
    },
    {
        "question": "Whose beauty is said to have been the cause of the Trojan War?","answer": "Helen"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country was England fighting against in the Battle of Agincourt?",
        "answer": "France"
    },
    {
        "question": "Many well-known figures fought in the Third Crusade. Which of these leaders died during this crusade?",
        "answer": "Frederick Barbarossa"
    },
    {
        "question": "In ROK, What is the prerequisite technology for the Herbal Medicine military technology?",
        "answer": "Camouflage"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following methods will NOT increase your academy's research speed?",
        "answer": "Justice Title"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Futhark rune represents \"r, the god of war and justice in Germanic mythology?",
        "answer": "Tiwaz"
    },
    {
        "question": "When sailing through a thunderstorm, one can occasionally see a \"lightning\" effect at the tip of the mast. What is this phenomenon called?",
        "answer": "Saint Elmo's Fire"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements about the tango is FALSE?",
        "answer": "It was created in the 15th century"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these commanders will gain a bonus from the Museum Relic \"Twin Dragons Inscription\"?",
        "answer": "Yi Seong-Gye"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following trees is commonly found in boreal ecosystems?",
        "answer": "Spruce"
    },
    {
        "question": "In ROK, What do you have to do to complete the quest \"Sword of the King\"?",
        "answer": "Recruit 200 infantry units"
    },
    {
        "question": "Iguazu Falls lies on the border of which two countries?",
        "answer": "Brazil and Agentina"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following events took place in North America during the Roaring Twenties?",
        "answer": "The \"Weird Tales\" magazine was first published"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following stories is not included in \"One Thousand and One Nights\"?",
        "answer": "Layla and Majnun"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these following methods will NOT increase your academy's research speed?",
        "answer": "Becoming your kingdom's Justice"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who kills Odin, the king of the gods, during Ragnarok in Norse mythology",
        "answer": "Fenrir"
    },
    {
        "question": "What two countries together made up the\"Iberian Union\"",
        "answer": "Portugal and Spain"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the father of Edward of Woodstock",
        "answer": "Edward III of England"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of Mulan's skills",
        "answer": "Clever Heart, Indomitable Army"
    },
    {
        "question": "The four biggest musicals in the world are Cats, Les Miserables, Miss Saigon, and...",
        "answer": "The Phantom of the Opera"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these two were created by Leonardo da Vinci","answer": "The Last Supper, Mona Lisa"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who founded the Kamakura shogunate?",
        "answer": "Minamoto no Yorttomo"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the largest airport in the world by area?",
        "answer": "King Fahd International Airport"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the renewable energy derived from burning organic materials such as wood and alcohol",
        "answer": "Biomass energy"
    },
    {
        "question": "Why were the bow and stern of Viking longboats designed to be symmetrical",
        "answer": "To reverse direction quickly without a turn around"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these commanders is often described as having survived 57 engagements without a single defeat?",
        "answer": "Honda"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following can NOT be found in Alliance Shops",
        "answer": "Golden Key"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which film won Outstanding Picture at the first ever Oscars",
        "answer": "Wings"
    },
    {
        "question": "In ancient Greek mythology, who was the wife of Hades, the king of the underworld",
        "answer": "Persephone"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country hosted the first ever Winter Olympics on January 25, 1924",
        "answer": "France"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following works was written by the French playwright Pierre Corneille",
        "answer": "Le Cid"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these is one of Minamoto no Yoshitsune's \"Active Skills\"",
        "answer": "Kyohachiryu"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is considered one of Confucius' disciples",
        "answer": "Yan Hui"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state is home to the Walt Disney Company",
        "answer": "California"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following inventions did NOT come about during the first industrial Revolution",
        "answer": "The telephone"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the Turkish straits that divide Europe from Asia",
        "answer": "The Bosphorus"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many items of the same quality should I equip to complete \"Ready for Battle\"",
        "answer": "6"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Ark of Osiris, how many teleports does the first alliance to occupy an obelisk earn",
        "answer": "8"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the original purpose of the Great Pyramid of Giza",
        "answer": "Pharoah Khufu's tomb"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the Babylonian Codes of Law was the first full set of written laws in recorded history",
        "answer": "The Code of Hammurabi"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following types of bonuses do NOT take effect in Ark of Osiris?",
        "answer": "Rune Buffs"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ashoka the Great was the king of which Ancient Indian kingdom",
        "answer": "Maurya"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which honorary rank was the founder of Kentucky Fried Chicken (KFC) given",
        "answer": "Colonel"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these is NOT considered one of the \"Five Good Emperors\" of the Nerva-Antonine dynasty of ancient Rome",
        "answer": "Commodus"
    },
    {
        "question": "Pandas have 5 clawed toes on as well as a sixth digit. What do pandas use their sixth digit for",
        "answer": "to hold Bamboo while eating"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT a suit in poker",
        "answer": "Winds"
    },
    {
        "question": "Hieroglyphs were part of which country's formal writing system",
        "answer": "Ancient Egypt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following constetlations is shaped like a crown?",
        "answer": "Corona Borealis"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which commander is known as \"The Immortal Hammer\"",
        "answer": "Charles Martel"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a man with type AB blood and a woman with type B blood have a baby, which of the following statements would be incorrect",
        "answer": "It could have type O blood"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where did reggae music originate",
        "answer": "Jamaica"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which vitamin deficiency can cause night blindness?",
        "answer": "Vitamin A"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the \"Gather Resources\" stage of the Mightiest Governor event, how many points do you get for gathering 1 Gem?",
        "answer": "150"
    },
    {
        "question": "With whom did Minamoto no Yoshitsune raise an army to fight Taira no Kiyomori",
        "answer": "Minamoto no Yoritomo"
    },
    {
        "question": "Mutations are important because they bring about what",
        "answer": "Genetic Variation needed for a population to evolve"
    },
    {
        "question": "Sandro Botticelli's painting \"Venus and Mars\" is famed for its vivid colors and beautiful figures. In which gallery is this painting now housed?",
        "answer": "The National Gallery in London"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of Julius Caesar's skills?",
        "answer": "Military Life"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Commander's active skill can inflict Silence",
        "answer": "Hermann"
    },
    {
        "question": "What age did ancient Greece enter after the Mycenaean civilization was destroyed",
        "answer": "Dark Age"
    },
    {
        "question": "The famous Renaissance sculpture Piet\u00c3\u00a4 was the work of which artist?",
        "answer": "Michelangelo"
    },
    {
        "question": "When Achilles refuses to fight, Patroclus puts on Achilles armor, fights the trojans, and dies, who is Patroclus killed by",
        "answer": "Hector"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following commanders in ROK was the only ruler in history to defeat Cyrus the Great in a major battle?",
        "answer": "Tomyris"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following awards daily activity points",
        "answer": "Defeating barbarian troops on the map"
    },
    {
        "question": "Held in 1929, how long did the first Academy Awards (\"Oscars\") ceremony take",
        "answer": "15 minutes"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the tallest peak in the world?",
        "answer": "Mount Everest"
    },
    {
        "question": "Halley's Comet can be observed from Earth every...",
        "answer": "75-76 years"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is considered a metallic resource",
        "answer": "Iron"
    },
    {
        "question": "After its foundation in the 6th century BCE, which institution of the Roman Republic served as a consultative parliament",
        "answer": "The Senate"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is the correct description for the stratosphere",
        "answer": "It is warm above and cold below"
    },
    {
        "question": "After the Lost Kingdom opens, What item do you have to spend to teleport to and from the Lost Kingdom?",
        "answer": "Random Teleport"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many Olympic gold medals did African-American athlete Jesse Owens win in 1936",
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these Commanders gets the ability to convert some slain units into severely wounded units when attacking a city",
        "answer": "Charlemagne"
    },
    {
        "question": "The 24 \"solar terms\" are a traditional Chinese calendar system used for What purpose?",
        "answer": "Agriculture"
    },
    {
        "question": "Charles Macintosh crafted a very early version of a raincoat from which material",
        "answer": "Rubber"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these is NOT considered one of the \"Five Good Emperors\" of the Nerva-Antonine dynasty of ancient Rome",
        "answer": "Commodus"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the most abundant element in earth's crust",
        "answer": "Oxygen"
    },
    {
        "question": "In 1970, an Apollo mission attempted to land on the moon. Due to a technical issue, it only managed to orbit around the moon and return to Earth. What was the name of the mission?",
        "answer": "Apollo 13"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where did the final battle between King Arthur and Mordred take place according to Arthurian legend",
        "answer": "Camlann"
    },
    {
        "question": "In ROK, What is the nickname of the commander Constance?",
        "answer": "Queen of Sicily"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which technology comes right before Heavy Cavalry",
        "answer": "Scale Armor"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who wrote Alice's Adventures in Wonderland",
        "answer": "Lewis Carroll"
    },
    {
        "question": "In what year did Einstein publish his four Annus Mirabilis (\"Miracle Papers\" )",
        "answer": "1905"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the largest known planet in our solar system?",
        "answer": "Jupiter"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these novels was NOT written by Margaret Atwood?",
        "answer": "Flowers of Algernon"
    },
    {
        "question": "Before leading the biggest slave rebellion of Ancient Rome, what was Spartacus",
        "answer": "Gladiator"
    },
    {
        "question": "A human fingernail is made of which material",
        "answer": "Alpha-keratin"
    },
    {
        "question": "By what other name is October also known under Japan's old calendar",
        "answer": "Kannazuki"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of Matilda of Flanders'skills",
        "answer": "Celtic Blood"
    },
    {
        "question": "After the students at the Lyceum of Wisdom finish their lessons, what building in your city do they return to?",
        "answer": "Academy"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who wrote the well-known book \"Sapiens: A Brief History of Humankind\"",
        "answer": "Yuval Noah Harari"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which city hosted the 2000 Summer Olympics",
        "answer": "Sydney"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these animated movies was NOT directed by Hayao Miyazaki",
        "answer": "Paprika"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many dispatches do you need to complete at the State Forum to open a Dispatch Commendation?",
        "answer": "15"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these is one of Minamoto no Yoshitsune's \"Active Skills\"",
        "answer": "Kyohachiryu"
    },
    {
        "question": "What animal is the \"Tigris\" named after in ancient Greek",
        "answer": "Tiger"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many daily Activity Points do you need in \"Lucerne Scrolls\" to claim the Daily Gift reward",
        "answer": "50"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following was praised by his countrymen as Ancient Greece's best and most honest democratic representatives",
        "answer": "Pericles"
    },
    {
        "question": "In ancient Egypt, which of the following was NOT a privilege of being a 'Scribe",
        "answer": "Exempt from paying medical expenses if sick"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these animated movies was NOT directed by Hayao Miyazaki?",
        "answer": "Paprika"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Japan, \"torii\" gates are usually placed at the entrance of what buildings?",
        "answer": "Shinto shrines"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many days are in a leap year?",
        "answer": "366"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which two oceans does the Panama Canal connect",
        "answer": "The Pacific and Atlantic Oceans"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these countries did NOT participate in the Northern Seven Years' War (1563-1570)",
        "answer": "The United Kingdom"
    },
    {
        "question": "Shanghai's Jin Mao Tower has how many floors",
        "answer": "88"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following musical instruments has six strings",
        "answer": "Guitar"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following types of bonuses do NOT take effect in Ark of Osiris?",
        "answer": "Rune Buffs"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Sunset Canyon, how many troops can you deploy at a time?",
        "answer": "5"
    },
    {
        "question": "What useful tool did famed carpenter Lu Ban invent",
        "answer": "The saw"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the largest living species of bird in the world?",
        "answer": "Ostrich"
    },
    {
        "question": "At What level does the Trading Post's transport tax rate become 10%?",
        "answer": "24"
    },
    {
        "question": "The city decoration \"Ishtar Gate\" is a tribute to which of the following civilizations?",
        "answer": "Babylonia"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the capital of the Germany",
        "answer": "Berlin"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the in-game nickname of Cleopatra VII",
        "answer": "Queen of Egypt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT a component ingredient used to forge the Epic weapon \"Golden Age\"?",
        "answer": "Animal Bone"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following constetlations is shaped like a crown?",
        "answer": "Corona Borealis"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Ark of Osiris, what is the requirement for an alliance to participate in the Golden Battlefield",
        "answer": "Ranked top 20 for alliance power in their kingdom"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which year was the Soviet Union formally established",
        "answer": "1922"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following items can be used to upgrade a commander's skills?",
        "answer": "Commander Sculptures"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Chieftain in the Ceroli Crisis event mounted a successful coup",
        "answer": "Torgny"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is recognized by the Guinness Book of World Records as having the largest cumulative circulation of any single-author comic",
        "answer": "Eiichiro Oda / One Piece"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the revolution in 1688 which established the British constitutional monarchy",
        "answer": "Glorious Revolution"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which landmark in Sydney, Australia is shaped like sails",
        "answer": "Sydney Opera House"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these civilizations can increase their healing speed",
        "answer": "France"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following commanders was part of the Battle of Red Cliffs",
        "answer": "Cao Cao"
    },
    {
        "question": "Cactus spines are actually a modified form of which other part of the plant",
        "answer": "Leaves"
    },
    {
        "question": "The \"Beef Wellington\" involves cooking filet mignon wrapped inside which other ingredient",
        "answer": "Puff pastry"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the main ingredient in salt",
        "answer": "Sodium chloride"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the main ingredient of popcorn",
        "answer": "Corn"
    },
    {
        "question": "On which ingredient was the 1986 Mexico World Cup's mascot based on?",
        "answer": "Pepper"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which two cities does Portugal's Dom Luis I Bridge connect",
        "answer": "Porto, Vila Nova de Gaia"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following was written by Mary Shelley",
        "answer": "Frankenstein"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following does NOT increase an Alliance's member limit",
        "answer": "Appointing officers"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who wrote \"The Symposium\"",
        "answer": "Plato"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which astronomer proposed the heliocentric theory in the 16th century",
        "answer": "Nicolaus Copernicus"
    },
    {
        "question": "At which VIP level do you permanently unlock a second building queue",
        "answer": "6"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which buff can be acquired from occupying a Sanctum of Courage",
        "answer": "Increase EXP gained by commanders"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the primary cause of karst landforms",
        "answer": "The dissolution of soluble rocks"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which prominent statesman served as the first Shogun of the Edo shogunate at the end of Japan's Warring States period?",
        "answer": "Tokugawa"
    },
    {
        "question": "France and Germany were both once part of what feudal Kingdom",
        "answer": "Francia"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT one of Lohar's skills",
        "answer": "Utter Annihilation"
    },
    {
        "question": "In ROK, which commander is nicknamed \"Father of Conquest\"?",
        "answer": "Baibars"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Luger pistol, manufactured for the German army during WW2, uses which type of ammo",
        "answer": "9mm Parabellum"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country did Zarathustra, of the tone poem 'Thus Spoke Zarathustra' , come from",
        "answer": "Persia"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the largest living species of bird in the world?",
        "answer": "Ostrich"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who founded the \"Spanish Armada\"",
        "answer": "Philip II"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where are the world's largest proven oil reserves located",
        "answer": "Ghawar Field"
    },
    {
        "question": "Combat Tactics is an important Military Technology\u00e2\u20ac\u201dwhat effect does it have?",
        "answer": "Increases Attack of all units"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following describes a monotheist",
        "answer": "Someone who warships 1 god."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following commanders' sculptures cannot be donated to the \"Past Glory\" event after the Lost Kingdom has been opened?",
        "answer": "Aethelfled"
    },
    {
        "question": "Queen Guinevere fell in love with which Knight of the Round Table according to Arthurian legend",
        "answer": "Lancelot"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these is NOT considered a Shakespearean tragedy",
        "answer": "Twelfth Night"
    },
    {
        "question": "Mutations are important because they bring about what",
        "answer": "Genetic Variation needed for a population to evolve"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the Desire of Victory event, how can players gain rewards?",
        "answer": "Training Troops"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who founded the \"Malacca Sultanate\"",
        "answer": "Parameswara"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these novels was NOT written by Margaret Atwood?",
        "answer": "Flowers of Algernon"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which commander wields the Beauty and Wisdom skill?",
        "answer": "Cleopatra VII"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where was commander Lohar born",
        "answer": "In a remote barbarian tribe."
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is considered the \"Father of the Modern Olympic Games\"",
        "answer": "Pierre de Coubertin"
    },
    {
        "question": "The cathedral of Notre-Dame de Paris was built in which style?",
        "answer": "Gothic"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the simplified Maslow's hierarchy of needs, which need is at the top of the pyramid?",
        "answer": "Self-actualization"
    },
    {
        "question": "How do you get Alliance Technology Points",
        "answer": "By donating to research Alliance Technology"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which astronomer proposed the heliocentric theory in the 16th century",
        "answer": "Nicolaus Copernicus"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which buff can be acquired from occupying a Sanctum of Courage",
        "answer": "Increase EXP gained by commanders"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which commander is known as Barbarossa",
        "answer": "Frederick I"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following resources cannot be found in your jeans",
        "answer": "Lead"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who conquered the \"Kingdom of the Vandals and Alans\" in the Vandalic War",
        "answer": "Belisarius"
    },
    {
        "question": "Whose victory was the orchestral work \"1812 Overture\" composed to commemorate",
        "answer": "Russian Empire"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who commanded the New Model Army founded by Parliament during the English Civil War",
        "answer": "Cromwell"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT a \"Iow country\" of Europe",
        "answer": "The United Kingdom"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a \"light-year\" a measure of",
        "answer": "Distance"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which war was fought between the British houses of Lancaster and York for the throne of England",
        "answer": "The Wars of the Roses"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which country was air conditioning invented",
        "answer": "USA"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which composer wrote the opera \"The Ring of the Nibelung\"",
        "answer": "Wagner"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following does not award Individual Credits",
        "answer": "Giving resources to allies / Attacking Barbs"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which art group is known as a \"National Treasure\" of Canada",
        "answer": "Cirque du Soleil"
    },
    {
        "question": "In ROK, which commander has the nickname \"Queen of Sicily\"?",
        "answer": "Constance"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following did NOT occur during the Greco-Persian Wars",
        "answer": "The Battle of Agincourt"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following Fish lures its prey through bioluminescence?",
        "answer": "Angler Fish"
    },
    {
        "question": "Mutations are important because they bring about what",
        "answer": "Genetic Variation needed for a population to evolve"
    }
]